Guide to the Francis Warrington Dawson Family Papers, 1386-1963, bulk 1859-1950 RL.10147
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1859-1963 and undated
  - Diplomatic Papers, 2 boxes
    A group of transcripts of diplomatic dispatches of Comte Louis Barbe Charles Serurier, French minister in Washington, to Talleyrand, Oct., 1812-June, 1813, describe the opening phrases of the War of 1812, United States opinion concerning France, the divorce proceedings of Elizabeth (Patterson) Bonaparte, interviews with Secretary of State James Monroe, Joel Barlow's negotiations for a commercial treaty with France, embargo, non-importation, and impressment; Republican and Federalist activities; and affairs in New Granada (Columbia). A later series of dispatches from the French minister in Washington, Alphonse J. Y. Pageot, 1835-1848, relates to American spoliation claims against France, American public opinion, analyses of nullification, the Bank of the United States crisis, abolition, and other aspects of American politics. Dispatches of 1841-1843 from Madrid contain information on Spanish affairs, and the guardianship and marriage of the Spanish queen. Later dispatches from Washington concern commercial relations between France and the United States; annexation of Texas and Oregon; the Mexican War and the question of slavery in the territories and its implications for disunion; and the war's effect on French commerce.
    - Dawson II: Miscellaneous diplomatic cables/drafts, 1929, undated (Box 87)
    - Dawson II: Diplomatic cables (0000000-0000029), 1946 Dec. 10- 1948 Mar. 6 (Box 87)
      Includes cable index.
    - Dawson II: Diplomatic cables (0000030-0000086), 1948 Mar. 8 - 1950 May 10 (Box 87)
    - Dawson II: Diplomatic cables (7001-7047), 1950 Jun 12 - 1951 Jan. 21 (Box 87)
    - Dawson II: Diplomatic cables (7048-7108), 1951 Feb. 18 - 1952 Apr. 6 (Box 87)
    - Dawson II: Diplomatic cables (7110-7152), 1952 Apr. 10 - 1953 Nov. 7 (Box 87)
    - Dawson II: Diplomatic cables (7154-7197), 1954 Jan. - 1958 Dec. (Box 87)
    - Diplomatic correspondence: Alphonse Pageot dispatches to Duc de Broglie, NY-DC, 1835 (Box 88)
    - Diplomatic correspondence: Clippings about Pageot/Broglie, 1836-1837 (Box 88)
    - Diplomatic correspondence: Pageot-Gonzales correspondence - Madrid, 1841 (Box 88)
    - Diplomatic papers: Memos from Alphonse Pageot re: Spanish marriages, 1842 (Box 88)
    - Diplomatic papers from Alphonse Pageot, 1843 (Box 88)
    - Diplomatic correspondence of Alphonse Pageot, 1847-1848 (Box 88)
    - Diplomatic papers: Direction Commerciale, 1, 5, 8-10, 25, 44-45, 1843-1845 (Box 88)
    - Diplomatic papers - #76-107, Alphonse Pageot, 1845 (Box 88)
    - Diplomatic papers - #149-214, Alphonse Pageot, 1847-1848 (Box 88)
- Photographs, 1
  This collection contains photographs of the Dawson family, friends and acquaintances, as well as photographs collected as a part of Warrington Dawson's research. Present are photographs of Joseph and Jessie Conrad, Warrington Dawson, Sarah Dawson, Ethel (Dawson) Barry, Herbert Barry, Frank Dawson, Daniel H. Chamberlain (Reconstruction governor of South Carolina), François Millet, Woodrow Wilson, Archibald Forbes, Lord Windsor, the Chateau de Josselin (signed by the Duke and Duchess de Rohan), historical monuments and their inscriptions in Virginia, the Charleston earthquake, and Warrington Dawson's Versailles apartment.
  - Dawson Family Photographs, 1
    - Barry, Herbert Sr.; drawing by Herbert Barry Jr., 1898, undated (Box 84)
    - Berry, Eleanor, 1884, undated (Box 84)
    - Dawson, Francis Warrington, I, 1859-1874, undated (Box 84)
    - Berry, Herbert Jr. with Eleanor Barry, 1878-1937, undated; 4 folders (Box 84)
      Photographs span from seven months old to adulthood. Also includes sickbed photos and photos of Dawson receiving the Commander's Cravate in 1930.
    - Dawson, Sarah Morgan, 1886, undated (Box 84)
    - undated (Box 84)
    - Sarah Morgan Dawson with Eleanor Barry., undated (Box 84)
    - Drum, Blossom, 1878 (Box 84)
      Blossom Drum became Mrs. Henry J. Hunt. Photograph contains geneology on reverse side.
    - Morgan, James Morris, undated (Box 84)
      Brother of Sarah Morgan Dawson.
    - Reeks, Joseph Austin, undated (Box 84)
      Father of F.W. Dawson, I.
    - Reeks, Joseph William, undated (Box 84)
      Brother of F.W. Dawson, I.
    - [Warrington Dawson with William Graves Sharp][?], George Clough Sharp, 1916, undated (Box 84)
      Noted on mount that this photograph seems to be of Warrington Dawson.
    - White, Teresa Mary, undated (Box 84)
      Sister of F.W. Dawson, I.
    - F.W. Dawson, II. Swedish Dance, 1890s (Box 86)
    - Barry, Herbert, Jr. and Barry, Stuyvesant, 1898, 1908 (Box 86)
      Accompanied by handwritten notes from Warrington Dawson (dated 1959) with biographical information.
    - Charcoal Sketches of F.W. Dawson, II by Gaetan de Navacelle, 1930 (Box 86)
      Accompanied by handwritten note from Warrington Dawson (dated 1959) with further information.
    - Memorial Window and Deathbed Photograph of Sarah Morgan Dawson, 1909 (Box 86)
      Accompanied by handwritten note from Warrington Dawson (dated 1959) with further information, including his whereabouts at her death and a vision she had of what her deathbed would look like.
    - Miscellaneous Oversize Photographs (Box 100)
  - Photographs Collected as Research Materials, undated
    Photographs, pictures of portraits, busts, sketches, etc. depicting with Revolutionary War figures, French soldiers, Williamsburg, and Yorktown.
    - New York City and V.P.: Early Views (Box 78)
    - Williamsburg, Virginia: Restoration pictures, 1928 (Box 78)
    - Williamsburg, Virginia: Wren Building, 1930, undated (Box 78)
    - Balme, Augustin-Nuttin de la, undated (Box 78)
    - French Soldier's Uniforms, undated (Box 78)
    - Franklin, Benjamin, undated (Box 78)
    - Rochambeau Family, undated (Box 78)
    - Gilbert du Motier, Marquis de Lafayette, undated (Box 78)
    - Yorktown, Virginia: Battle Monuments, etc., undated (Box 78)
    - Rochambeau Headquarters at Newburgh - Restored, undated (Box 78)
    - Early Boston, undated (Box 78)
    - Miscellaneous Revolutionary Period Images, undated (Box 78)
    - Francois Marie Comte d'Aboville, 1790 (Box 78)
    - Hubert, Comte de Goy de Begues, undated (Box 78)
    - Washington, George, undated (Box 78)
    - Repentigny, Louis Marquis de, undated (Box 78)
    - Goodwin, William Archer Rutherford, undated (Box 78)
    - Foch, Ferdinand, undated (Box 78)
    - St. Hypolite, Jacques-Philippe-Paudin de Biarces (Box 78)
    - Lafayette College; Society of American Friends of Lafayette, 1932 (Box 78)
    - Dentzel, George Frederic, undated (Box 78)
    - Vue de Versailles, undated (Box 78)
    - Paintings by Nicolas Poussin, undated (Box 78)
    - Kuningam, Augustatus, undated (Box 78)
    - Miscellaneous Oversize Photographs (Box 100)
  - Charleston earthquake photographs, 1886 (Image 1)
    Arrangement note
    These images are mounted on cardboard and are approximately 16x20 inches, unless otherwise noted. They are arranged in four oversize boxes, which have been numbered in the catalog as Image Boxes 1-4. Most photographs were taken by C.C. Jones of the U.S. Geological Survey on August 31, 1886. Some photographs have additional captions, added later, written on their cardboard mounts. At least two photographs are personal, and show the Dawson residence following the earthquake.
    - Broken cornice on St. Michael's Church, Southeast corner of Broad and Meeting Streets, Looking Southeast (Box 80)
    - Brick wall of the city Jail on Magazine Street near Luzon, fissured by earthquake (Box 80)
    - Double exposure of the Granite Works. Dominant image is a yard of granite monuments, some of which have been toppled by the earthquake. (Box 80)
    - Granite Works (Box 80)
    - Craterlet and curdled mud flakes on Ten Mile Hill (Box 80)
    - Sinkhole under a house on Ten Mile Hill (Box 80)
    - Displaced monument, St. John's Lutheran Church, Archdale Street, Looking South (Box 80)
    - Craterlet on Ten Mile Hill (Box 80)
    - Displaced portico of the synogogue on Hazel Street (Box 80)
    - Scotch Presbyterian Church, Cemetary, and Convent (Box 81)
    - Fissure and a wrecked brick house on Tradd Street (Box 81)
    - Gadsden House, Bishop's Residence, Broad Street (Box 81)
    - Wooden house in Lincolnville which was thrown by the earthquake (Box 81)
    - Camp in Courthouse Square, City Park, Broad Street and Meeting Street (Box 81)
    - Gable of a brick house at the corner of Queen and Mazyck Streets. (Box 81)
    - Displaced coping on the portico of the old guardhouse on the southwest corner of Meeting and Broad Streets (Box 81)
    - Hiberian Hall, Meeting Street (Box 81)
    - Displaced monument, St. John's Lutheran Church, Archdale Street, Looking North (Box 81)
    - Large craterlet on Ten Mile Hill (Box 82)
    - St. John's Lutheran Church, Archdale Street, Looking Southeast (Box 82)
    - Damaged tower and coping of the city hospital on the southwest corner of Luzon and Magazine Streets. (Box 82)
    - Damaged foundations of wooden houses (Box 82)
    - Displaced towers and coping of the city hospital on the southwest corner of Luzon and Magazine Streets (Box 82)
    - Damage to the Old Planter's Hotel, St. Philip's Church, Church Home, and Huguenot Church (Box 82)
    - Damaged chimneys at the southwest corner of Beaufin and Archdale Streets. (Box 82)
    - East Bay Street, with collapsed buildings (Box 82)
    - Encampment on Capt. Dawson's lawn (6x9 inch photograph) (Box 83)
    - Capt. Dawson's house (6x9 inch photograph) (Box 83)
- Warrington Dawson's Collection of French Manuscripts, 1386-1786; 4
  An avid collector of French manuscripts, this series includes Dawson's own personal collection he acquired during his time in France. Dawson's collection relates to his interest in genealogy and concern the de Bethune, de Crequi, Chevalier, and related families, and include a few parchments concerning Maximilien de Béthune, Duc de Sully, and Henry IV, King of France.
  - 13th century manuscript fragment. MS. (Box 73)
  - Arêt from King's Council. MS., 1679 (Box 74)
  - Bethune, Armand de. Memoirs. MS. (Box 73)
  - Bethune, Armand de. Letters & Coat of Arms. MS. (Box 73)
  - Bethune, Armand-Louis de. Orders of seizure of property. MS, TS., 1785-1786 (Box 73)
  - Bethune, Armand-Louis de. Assets for successor. MS., 1781 (Box 73)
  - Bethune cadet branch. Letters. MS. (Box 73)
  - Bethune-Charost branch. MS., 1718-1804 (Box 73)
  - Bethune de Caulincourt, Duchess de. Letters to Duke of Sully. MS. (Box 73)
  - Bethune, Duke de. Letter. MS., 1746 (Box 73)
  - Bethune, Francois de & Jacqueline de Caurment. Sale of house. MS. (Box 73)
  - Bethune, Francois de. Order for Martin de Bidault entering order of St. Michael. MS., 1657 Dec 24 (Box 73)
  - Bethune genealogy. MS. (Box 73)
  - Bethune, Louise de. Document. MS. (Box 73)
  - Bethune, Maximilien Alphin de. Document. MS., 1660 Jun 23 (Box 73)
  - Bethune, M.A. Armde de. Military commission. TS, MS., 1751 (Box 74)
  - Bethune, Maximilien-Antoine Armand de. Receipt. MS., 1747 (Box 73)
  - Bethune, Maximilien-Alphin de. Lawsuit before Parliamnent. MS., 1678 (Box 73)
  - Bethune, Maximilien de, Duc de Sully. Letters. MS., 1788 Apr 16, Aug 29 (Box 73)
  - Bethue, Maximilien de, Duc de Sully. Receipt. MS., 1610 Nov 10 (Box 73)
  - Bethune, Maximilien de, Duc de Sully. Engraving and letter. MS., 1599 (Box 73)
  - Bethune, Maximilien Francois de. Decree. MS, TS., 1656, Jan 1 (Box 73)
  - Bethune, Maximilien Henri de. Legal documents. MS., 1727 (Box 73)
  - Cabot, Henry. Duc de Rohan-Chabot. MS., 1648 (Box 74)
  - Caumont, Henry-Jacques de. Documents, 1697-1767 (Box 74)
  - Charles VII, King of France. Parchments, 1458, 1461 (Box 79)
  - Chartres, Bishop of. Church document., 1712 (Box 74)
  - Chevalier, Denis & Abbe de Tournay. Sale of estate grounds of Tournay. MS., 1763-1767. (Box 73)
  - Cochefillet, Rachel de. Document. MS., 1631 (Box 73)
  - Cochefillet, Rachel de. Letter to M. Nichols. MS, TS., 1624 Oct 6 (Box 73)
  - Courval genealogy. MS. (Box 74)
  - Coutenount, Madeline Armand d., Duchese de Sully. Receipt. MS., 1714 (Box 73)
  - Crequi, Antoine de. Eveque de Nantes. MS., 1559 (Box 79)
  - de Crequi family. MS. (Box 74)
  - de Crequi family. MS. (Box 74)
  - De la Haye genealogy. MS. (Box 73)
  - Duc de Berri, regent of France., 1386 Apr 27 (Box 74)
  - Duke de Sully. Bill of Sale. MS., 1767 (Box 74)
  - Duke de Sully. Legal document- estate. MS, 1706 (Box 74)
  - Estate of Tournay, papers. MS., 1566-1703 (Box 73)
  - French army commissions & discharges. MS. (Box 74)
  - French army sale of a regiment. MS., 1706 (Box 74)
  - Henri de Barillon, Bishop of Lucan. Installation of Julien de Valgreville as prior of monastary of St. Cyprian, Poitiers. MS., 1673, Jan 14 (Box 73)
  - Henry III. Royal decree, 1580 Nov (Box 79)
  - Henry IV, King of Navarre. Letter to Sully. MS., 1608 May 12 (Box 73)
  - Henry IV, King of Navarre. List of officials and their salaries. MS., 1605 (Box 73)
  - Inventory of estate and succession, notarized. MS., 1709-1711 (Box 73)
  - Jouvenal des Ursins, Francois. Letter to Sully. MS., 1615 Nov 29 (Box 73)
  - Louis XIV, 1706 (Box 79)
  - Louis, Duc d'Orleans. Legal document. MS., 1740, Jul 19 (Box 74)
  - Maps of Tournay. MS. (Box 73)
  - Notes and letters. MS., 1691-1708 (Box 73)
  - d'Orval, Armand. Letter to his brother, Abbe d'Orval. MS., 1680 May 23 (Box 73)
  - d'Orleans, Francois. Survey of estate of Varengueher. MS., 1575 May 16 (Box 73)
  - Pierce, Louis & Maximilien de Bethune. Notes. MS., 1709-1732 (Box 73)
  - Porte, Catherine de la. Receipt. MS., 1706 (Box 73)
  - Printed materials (Box 74)
  - Rothelin. Normandie-Familiies d'Orleans. (Box 73)
  - Rothelin. Legal documents. MS., 1691 (Box 73)
  - Sein de Rothelin. Military commission. TS, MS., 1717 (Box 79)
  - Sully, Duke de. Letters. MS., 1737 (Box 73)
- Warrington Dawson's Research Files
  This is a collection of Warrington Dawson's research on a number of topics, including family genealogy, Revolutionary War research, his research on Williamsburg, and miscellaneous research notes.
  - Genealogical Research, undated; 5 folders (Box 59)
    Various documents, records, family notes and notebooks related to the Dawson genealogy. Contains genealogical papers of the Morgan family and related Gibbes, Fowler, Waller, Hunt, Bunyan, and Baynton families, including a chart of the Reeks family of England. Some manuscript, some typescript.
  - Revolutionary War Research
    Warrington Dawson's research on the Revolutionary War. Includes copies, photostats, handwritten extracts, and typescripts of journals, correspondence, geneologies, maps, and other research on the topic.
    - Miscellaneous Journal Extracts of French Officers, 1781, 1788, undated; 1 folders (Box 75)
    - Maps of Virginia, Williamsburg, Yorktown, 1755, 1781, undated; 1 folders (Box 75)
    - Research on the Campaign of 1781, 1781, undated; 1 folders (Box 75)
    - Research on the Baron de Viomenil, 1770, 1782, 1819, undated; 1 folders (Box 75)
    - Letters of Armand-Louis de Gontant, Duc de Lanzun, 1781; 1 folders (Box 75)
    - Journal Historique Concernant [...] les Expeditions de M. le Comte de Grasse, 1781; 1 folders (Box 75)
    - Documents regarding Louis Gaspard de Repentigny, 1822, undated; 1 folders (Box 75)
    - Memoirs du chevalier de Saint-Cyr, 1815; 2 folders (Box 75)
    - Research on Claude-Anne, Marquis de Saint-Simon, 1932, undated; 1 folders (Box 75)
    - Miscellaneous Dossiers of French Officers and Research, 1881, 1931, undated; 1 folders (Box 75)
    - Journal of Baron Gaspard de Gallatin, 1780-1781; 1 folders (Box 75)
    - Geneology of the Comte de Grasse, 1563-1918; 1 folders (Box 75)
    - Journal of Pierre Durousseau de Fayolle, 1777-1779; 1 folders (Box 75)
    - Lafayette Letters and Papers, 1777, 1782, 1786,1837, undated; 1 folders (Box 76)
    - A Journal of the Siege of Savannah, 1779; 1 folders (Box 76)
    - Rochambeau: Journal of the Staff at the Siege of Yorktown, VA, 1781; 1 folders (Box 76)
    - Rochambeau: Officers in Army on American Expedition, undated; 1 folders (Box 76)
    - Rochambeau: Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1781-1783; 2 folders (Box 76)
    - Letters of George Washington, 1778-1784; 1 folders (Box 76)
    - Letters of and Research on Benjamin Franklin, 1776-1788, undated; 1 folders (Box 76)
    - Guerre de l'Independence d'Amerique, undated; 1 folders (Box 76)
    - Material on Mathieu Dumas and Charles Esebeck, 1781, 1838; 1 folders (Box 76)
    - Research on Arthur and Edouard Dillon, 1881, undated; 1 folders (Box 76)
    - Research on Jean Coste and Claude Henri Ferdinand (Medical Staff), undated; 1 folders (Box 76)
    - Letters of Barras and Boisbrunet, 1781; 1 folders (Box 76)
    - Research on Augustin Mottin de la Baume, 1780, 1907, undated; 1 folders (Box 76)
    - Dossier and Correspondence of Comte d'Aboville, 1781-1783, undated; 1 folders (Box 76)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1781-1782; 1 folders (Box 77)
    - Archives and Resources, undated; 1 folders (Box 77)
    - French Societies, Patriotic Societies, American Societies, 1928-1930, undated; 1 folders (Box 77)
    - Family Histories, 17th century; 1 folders (Box 77)
    - Excerpts from Thomas Balch's "Les Francais en Amerique pendant la Guerre de l'Independence des Etats-Unis", 1872; 1 folders (Box 77)
    - French Dead in Revolutionary War, Lists of French Officers, 1778-1787, undated; 1 folders (Box 77)
    - Lists of French Dead, 1932; 1 folders (Box 77)
    - French Army in American Revolution: Lists of Maps, Marches, and Encampments; Miscellaneous Army Notes, 1781, undated; 1 folders (Box 77)
  - Williamsburg Research, 1930-1932; 23 folders (Box 89, 90)
    Contains Warrington Dawson's research on Williamsburg. Includes press clippings and releases, notes, research diary and research memos.
  - Miscellaneous Research, undated; 18 folders (Box 59)
    Miscellaneous research notes on a variety of subjects. Includes four folders of notes from Lillian Cridler Segonne, presumably Dawson's research assistant.
- Scrapbooks, 1853-1961; 3
  Primarily the scrapbooks of Sarah Morgan Dawson, who filled volumes with newpaper clippings by or about her husband Francis W. Dawson I, as well as letters to Captain Dawson and her own comments. Included in this series are also two autograph books of people who attended gatherings hosted by Warrington Dawson from 1909-1961. Arranged by date.
  - Dawson, Sarah Morgan. Newspaper clippings and handwritten notes., 1853-1882 (Box 67)
  - Dawson, Sarah Morgan. Newspaper clippings and letters to Francis Dawson. Charleston SC, 1875-1884 (Box 67)
  - Dawson, Sarah Morgan. Newspaper articles by Cap. Francis W. Dawson. Charleston, SC., 1880-1897 (Box 68)
  - Dawson, Warrington. Articles and Stories., 1910-1953 (Box 68)
  - Dawson, Warrington. Articles, etc., 1886-1952 (Box 97)
    Warrington Dawson's articles published in the News and Courier.
  - Dawson, Warrington. Reviews., 1904-1915 (Box 69)
  - Dawson, Warrington. Signature book., 1909-1961; 2 Volumes (Box 69)
  - Dawson, Sarah Morgan. "Talks By the Way" newspaper column., 1886-1887 (Box 70)
  - Dawson, Sarah Morgan. Newspaper clippings and letters. Charleston, SC., 1878-1888 (Box 70)
  - Dawson, Sarah Morgan. Clippings on Capt. Dawson's death for Helene Burdayaron, 1889-1893 (Box 71)
  - Dawson, Sarah Morgan. Clippings on Capt. Dawson's death, 1889-1893 (Box 71)
    Includes handwritten note, dated 1890, by Sarah Dawson detailing the provenance of the volume.
  - Dawson, Warrington. Newspaper clippings., 1930-1931 (Box 72)
- Writings, 1
  This is a collection of writings predominantly by the Dawson family and by friends and acquaintances by the family. It includes diaries, manuscript and typescript drafts, speeches and publications. There are manuscripts of writings by Sarah Dawson; manuscripts, fragments, lectures by Warrington Dawson and Theodore Roosevelt; a log and a diary of Roosevelt's African trip; Roosevelt's notes on the policy of his administration in regard to African Americans; extracts from letters and speeches which the former president supplied for use in connection with Dawson's book, Opportunity and Theodore Roosevelt; manuscripts of the book; essays and drafts by Jessie Conrad, Vance Thompson, and Georges Ladoux, among others.
  There are diaries of Warrington Dawson, 1898, 1914-1918, 1930-1931, 1934-1945 (4 vols.) and of Ethel Dawson, 1888-1891 (1 vol.). Warrington's reminiscences of World War I deal with the French intelligence service and attributes the origin of his illness and that of Woodrow Wilson to German biological warfare. A second reminiscence concerns his work for the American Embassy in the 1930s and his life in Paris under German occupation, and has information on the dietary work of B. Lytton-Bernard (Bernard Trappachuh). A third reminiscence gives a mystical interpretation of world events, 1932-1945.
  Sarah Dawson's manuscript diaries, 1862-1866, 6 vols. (largely published 1913), also include notes from ca. 1896-1906. There are notebooks of Sarah explaining her husband's death, a manuscript by Warrington Dawson commenting on the same subject, and biographical accounts of Frank Dawson and other family members. Other notebooks of Sarah Dawson, 4 vols., 1898-1908, concern her life, travel, and psychical phenomena. Arranged by author.
  - Dawson Family Writings, 1
    - Dawson, Ethel. Diary, 1888-1891 (Box 32)
      Manuscript. Includes typewritten note from Warrington Dawson with further information on the diary.
    - Dawson, Francis W. An American View of It: The Sectional Character of the Protective System, 1887 (Box 32)
      Typescript. Offprint of speech published in The News and Courier.
    - Dawson, Francis W. The Charleston Earthquake, 1886 (Box 32)
      Typescript. Offprint from the Augusta, Ga., Chronicle. 2 copies.
    - Dawson, Francis W. Contents of Box, 1886-1903 (Box 32)
      Manuscript.
    - Dawson, Francis W. Contents of a private box at the Bank of Charleston, 1887 May 28 (Box 32)
    - Dawson, Francis W. Dwelling, undated (Box 32)
    - Dawson, Francis W. [Florence Mayflower] (Box 32)
      Manuscript of untitled play.
    - Dawson, Francis W. Four Years in the Army and Navy of the Confederate States, undated (Box 32)
    - Dawson, Francis W. Ledger, 1867-1877 (Box 32)
    - Dawson, Francis W. Ledger, 1868-1886 (Box 32)
    - Dawson, Francis W. Ledger, 1886-1889 (Box 32)
    - Dawson, Francis W. Ledger, 1888 (Box 33)
    - Dawson, Francis W. Memo/Ledger, 1885 (Box 33)
    - Dawson, Francis W. Memos, undated (Box 33)
    - Dawson, Francis W. Memo Notebook, undated (Box 33)
    - Dawson, Francis W. Memo Book, 1867-1878 (Box 33)
    - Dawson, Francis W. Never Judge By Appearances, 1859, undated; 3 folders (Box 33)
      Manuscript of play.
    - Dawson, Francis W. Notes on Political Economy by Cairnes, 1874 Dec. (Box 34)
    - Dawson, Francis W. Personal Finance Summary, 1887-1889 (Box 34)
    - Dawson, Francis W. Poetry, 1860-1886; 3 folders (Box 34)
      Manuscript. Notes and personal writings, including poetry and dramatic scenes.
    - Dawson, Francis W. Providential Aspects of Slavery, 1888 Nov 11 (Box 34)
      Typescript. 2 copies
    - Dawson, Francis W. Reform in South Carolina, undated (Box 34)
      Typescript.
    - Dawson, Francis W. Speech before Gratten League, undated (Box 34)
    - Dawson, Francis W. Writing Notebook, undated (Box 34)
    - Dawson, Sarah Morgan. Journals, 1898-1908; 4 folders (Box 34)